<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Meditations</title>
 <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io"/>
 <updated>2017-12-18T00:20:01-06:00</updated>
 <id>http://yadudoc.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Yadu Nand B</name>
   <email>yadudoc1729@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Break. Fail. Shatter.</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/2015/09/08/break-fail-shatter"/>
   <updated>2015-09-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/2015/09/08/break-fail-shatter</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;There is no Joy without pain. No success without failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To truly experience success, one must first fail. Experience failure,
have life shattering experiences and rebuild from the pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One would be miserable if one were to expect life to be an unbroken
string of successes. A superior approach is to approach failures as
a trusted teacher, and learn from them. Learn not to make the same
mistake. Learn to be better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you’ve learnt from your mistakes and made no mistake, you might
still lose, such is life. Be strong when lightning strikes and burns
down the tree you cared for. Take risks and strive to fail faster, and
never risk all your chips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that when things shatter and shatter they will, you’ve been
given the chance to put things together better than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Decision</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/2015/08/13/decision"/>
   <updated>2015-08-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/2015/08/13/decision</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Life’s purpose to expand valid choices to choose from, and to actively engage in making decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If decisions were not made of our own volition, we are no different from cattle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expanding valid and viable choices allow you to enjoy life. If there were no decisions ahead of us, we’d be just existing, not living. To really live life there must be hard decisions ahead of us, that force us to think of outcomes and make a decision about which choice we take, and to live out the consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Story</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/2015/08/11/story"/>
   <updated>2015-08-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/2015/08/11/story</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am the author, the most avid reader and the hero of my story.
The captain of the ship, the one who calls the shots.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The value of others</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/2015/08/06/the-value-of-others"/>
   <updated>2015-08-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/2015/08/06/the-value-of-others</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;A thought experiment goes as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have lived a life filled with people and relationships.
Overnight, everyone else has disappeared, and you are the only person left on the planet.
Plant and animal life seems to not have been affected so food, shelter and clothing are not an issue.
For the first time you are truly alone.
Alone for the rest of your life.
What do you do ?
Does life have any meaning anymore ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you redefine life and a purpose for continued existence ?
Perhaps, it is only when you’ve lost something, that you truly realize it’s value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living as a member of a social structure we engage in activities that fulfill the expecatations of others.
These expectations are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Oh, wretched ephemeral race, children of chance and misery, why do you compel me to tell you what it would be most expedient for you not to hear? What is best of all is utterly beyond your reach: not to be born, not to be, to be nothing. But the second best thing for you is—to die soon.’&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Giant blazing ball of fire</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/2015/07/22/giant-blazing-ball-of-fire"/>
   <updated>2015-07-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/2015/07/22/giant-blazing-ball-of-fire</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;It is human nature to quickly accept even the most terrifying things.
Can you remember a moment in the recent past where it scared you
that there is a giant blazing ball of fire in the sky ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even scarier is the fact that it is a huge fusion reactor, which could easily
fit a million of our tiny little planet in itself. It is the largest self sustainging fusion reactor in our immediate vicinity, and it is burning itself away.
What is even more surprising is that for the same volume, the rate of energy released at the core of the sun is about a quarter that of the human body. With the immense volume of a star, this process still indirectly drives the wind, weather and life on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would be really cool, is if these giant balls of gases could be extinguished and used at some later time when we have the ability to do so. Some sort of practical way to reversibly poison the fusion reaction. There is the risk that some mad terrorist could hold the Sun hostage, or even the rise of a Super villain straight out of Gotham. Even with the risks the potential to stop, and later harvest the energy within Stars and potentially even delay the heat death of the Universe sounds like a great plan.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Ethics of food</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/2015/06/30/ethics-of-food"/>
   <updated>2015-06-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/2015/06/30/ethics-of-food</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;[Not proofread]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Human beings are lacking in the apparatus to harvest the most abundant source of energy on the Planet.
As a result, most organisms including us, ultimately depend on plant life to do this.
We happen to be able to consume both plant life as well other organisms for sustenance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being omnivores, we have a several choice on the source of our sustenance, and some may not be quite as ethical as others.
For example we could sustain ourselves by consuming meat from other human beings, but cannibalism is considered
terrible in most cultures/societies even when cannibalism is common amongst several species in nature.
In western cultures we typically don’t eat animals we keep as pets, such as dogs and cats.
I think that we have some difficulty with the concept of killing creatures that we empathize with for the sake of food,
while most of us feel no remorse when having either chicken or beef for dinner.
In fact we hardly ever think of the piece of meat on the dinner plate in term of living being(s) that were farmed and slaughtered on an industrial scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not clear to me why the idea of eating meat from chicken does not elicit the same mental response of horror as the idea of eating meat from another human being or even a cat.
Looking back at our history of slavery, I see how easily we could once treat one another as commodities to be bought, sold, and used and think of it as normal.
There are parallels to be drawn to what we did back then to ourselves and what we do now to the mute creatures that we’ve labelled as inferior forms of life.
Only these animals do not have the words to complain or the mind to organize a rebellion against their masters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My current stance is that I will only eat creatures that are not smart enough to be self aware.
I feel bad about this because even though they may not be capable of higher intelligence,
they definitely are aware of their surroundings, the horrible conditions they are subjected to,
and they most certainly are capable of experiencing pain.
I sometimes think that I’m a terrible person for having thought about these matters, and yet not completely giving up meat products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, we can all agree that treating animals poorly is bad. What about the act of killing them ?
The animal do have to die at some point, what if they are killed (painlessly or not) at the peak age?
Would the gift of existence alone justify having brought these being to life for the purpose of feeding us ?
The more I think on this topic even more complications arise simply from the fact that we are bringing new sentient life into the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[TODO : Cleanup -&amp;gt; ]
What if these farmed animals are treated fairly, given a far better life than they could have in the wild with no natural predators,
fairly unlimited food, and freedom to reproduce. What if the only bargain, is that in return they are subjected to premature termination.
Would that be ethical? It is certainly not possible to have these creatures choose between no existence vs a cushy life and then being painlessly terminated. This is partly because, the choice to exist only becomes available only after the being has come into existence. Secondly we do not have any means to meaningfully communicate with these creatures and assert whether the ones that we have brought to life do prefer to exist rather than not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that if I were to ask any person if they would prefer a duration of existence interspersed with pleasure and pain in varying degrees over the absolute of not existing, most would choose to exist. This question is a bit absurd because, if anyone were to truly think that
non-existence is better, they could choose to terminate their existence, but this I think is very rare. Only when human beings are pushed to extremes of pain, over time, and with no hope of improving their situation do people opt to end their existence, while the vast majority hold
on dearly to their existence and try to prolong their existence. So asking these individuals if they would choose to bring to existence beings which are mostly limited in the range of experience but existing nonetheless is a rigged question. Another possibility is that since we exist, and cannot comprehend what it means to not-exist, we inherently fear it, and we cannot quite compare the two choices clearly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These choices are very relevant when it comes to raising animals for the sole purpose of culling them later in their lifecycle for food. These creatures have limited thought processes which probably limit them from understanding the purpose for which they are being farmed. They could be treated humanely, and made to suffer little to no pain. At which point, I think the collective weight of bringing to existence countless new minds however limited far outweighs not doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Increasing the collective mass of being which can experience things by itself is a purpose worthy of some medieval age religious zeal. For now besides siring a large number of offspring, the next best thing is to eat meat and indirectly support the animal farms.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Rent</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/life/2015/06/29/rent"/>
   <updated>2015-06-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/life/2015/06/29/rent</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;There’s no free lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the least ambiguous facts about existence as a self-aware conscious living being is that you are pretty sure that you exist.
To continue existing as a living being with our organic bodies we have to feed and maintain ourselves. This is a rent that comes implicitly with an organic body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mind in all its complexity is no different. The mind craves human contact, and things to entertain itself with. The rent we pay is a lot more subtle here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder if the concept of having to pay for the things you consume is a idea that comes from living in an economic system that society has created, or if it is inherent to any system of consumers and limited consumables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do we owe anything to the world for our existence ? Say, a moral or ethical debt/rent that we owe for having provided us the means to exist and by extention the means to impact some change and experience various things. We certainly did not cause our own existence. Like many thoughts I put down here, these questions are very subjective, and rather than find an answer or the right answer the point is to have pondered over them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since one does not cause one’s existence it is easy to argue that the responsibility and debt for the new being does not lie with the being but with the progenitors. In several cultures it is the norm to have children bear a sort of obligation to the parents for them being the sole reason for their existence. I think that is a cruel form of enslavement. I think that any expectation of a debt owed from creating a conscious being is ethically wrong. At the same time, the question of whether the new being should think of having owed anything is slightly more nuanced and is a matter of opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking in terms of parents, children and human beings might invoke current sense of morals/ethics inherited from our present social structure, so let’s thinkin terms of creating a new race of conscious machines (macs) . Like human beings, the macs come into existence with no preprogrammed purpose. The macs, need electricity and parts to survive and maintain themselves (food + medical care).
Ethically would the macs owe their creators anything ? We’ve sort of established that it would be unethical for the human creators to wish for this new race of beings to be their slaves.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Solitude</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/life/2015/06/23/solitude"/>
   <updated>2015-06-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/life/2015/06/23/solitude</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;From a mountain temple
the sound of bell struck fumblingly
vanishes in the mist.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On boredom</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/2015/06/03/on-boredom"/>
   <updated>2015-06-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/2015/06/03/on-boredom</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I’ve always felt that waiting in queue for the rollercoaster ride is the experience you pay for.
The anticipation builds up as you hear the screams draw closer and suddenly further away as the
ride snakes its way back to the end. The crescendo is when you are strapped in and the ride starts,
you experience first hand what you imagined it to be when you were waiting in queue.
5 minutes into a rollercoaster ride, the mechanical contraption has done everything it can do, and
I find myself thinking “Is that it ? Is it done ? When does this stop ? I need to get off this one
so that I can queue up for the next ride”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a programmer, an okay programmer. In my work, which consumes most of my waking hours, I find
myself going over a routine. I get excited about an idea, an idea that I can implement and bring
to reality. The anticipation of engineering something and making it work is a great feeling. The
singular focus on programming a sequence of logical steps to bring what was just an idea to something
concrete is just as fun. All this is pales in comparison to the rush from seeing your little creation
work, and soon the joy fades, the challenge has ended and I revert to the basis state, a state of boredom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the pleasures of the world that I know of, follow this pattern. Every single one. And it irks
me to no end that there is no sustainable way to get out of it. I realized that I might hate the
world for being inadequate entertainment. I wondered why it has to be so, why must there be no way
out of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The realization that it was me, not the world was obvious in hindsight. And it was just not me,
it was everyone, it was the nature of every normal living being. We adapt to what we have, hedonic
adaptation is what the learned folks call it. The new high becomes the basis, or in looking at it
another way, the state of being bored is our base state, and it our nature to crave to get a high.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Darmok and Jalad at Tanagra</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/2015/02/17/darmok-and-jalad-at-tanagra"/>
   <updated>2015-02-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/2015/02/17/darmok-and-jalad-at-tanagra</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I have arguments with my father over seemingly very minor things. These verbal scuffles
rarely result in any considerable change in perspective or new understanding. Most of these
tend to be misunderstandings of a fine point that both of us thought to be obvious to the other.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Legacy</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/2014/12/18/legacy"/>
   <updated>2014-12-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/2014/12/18/legacy</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the music that triggered this dump: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5p40pPd-UPc&quot;&gt;The Song of the Sibyl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though I do not understand a word in the music, the emotions are clear, the music describes the biblical apocalype,
the end of the world and in a way, the individual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thought that existence as I understand it will end someday truly frightens me. It also brings
a sense of urgency that I must make the most of life before the clock has run down. From the perspective of
the individual there are experiences to be had, goals to be achieved and a life to be lived and almost on the
other side is what must be left behind in the world for when your time has passed. While these aspects needn’t
be completely antithetical, with the limited resources at our disposal, sacrifices must be made on one for the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not think that accepting defeat in the face of the minuscule possibility that one’s actions might have some
profound impact on the trajectory of the human race is an honorable strategy. I exist here and now, and I want
to ensure that I take actions that will leave the most impact in the future. Then the question becomes, what do
I want my legacy to be ? What do I do to make that happen ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following is not refined:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Money
I grew up in a situation where there was just enough to be comfortable, my parents made sure of that.
You couldn’t want something you didn’t know existed, and much of modern day luxuries were off the table.
There was a constant reminder that finances are tight, and the way out is education and success. Adversity
is a compelling reason to work hard. I believe that I’m no longer at risk of financial troubles, but I would
not take risks that involve compromising heavily on finances, such as going for a Ph.D.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To truly chase after dreams, financial stability is necessary, and building a foundation that grants
this to the next generation is in my opinion, a worthy goal. While this runs the risk of being coddled by
an inherited security, it is far better setting up a situation of continued&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Becalmed</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/2014/09/02/becalmed"/>
   <updated>2014-09-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/2014/09/02/becalmed</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;You are at the sea, surrounded by the warmth of unhindered sunshine of a summer day.
There is the gentle roll of the waves, the occassional squaking of a hungry seagull.
There is calm, the comfort of the routine, and the certainity that you are not going anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no wind in the sails and no harbor to call home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My idle brain is this ship, lost in the sea, aimless without a bearing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Repertoire of classy insults</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/2014/08/23/repertoire-of-classy-insults"/>
   <updated>2014-08-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/2014/08/23/repertoire-of-classy-insults</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Scraped from reddit for the most part:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I can explain it to you, but I can’t comprehend it for you”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I love how you state the obvious, with such a sense of discovery”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’d like to agree with you, but then we would both be wrong”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do not speak unless you intend to improve the silence, please”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You make me feel like a better person”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When a savage speaks, silence will suffice”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I refuse to have a batle of wits against an unarmed opponent”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh honey, you are not pretty enough to be that stupid”&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Paper planes</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/2014/08/08/Paper-planes"/>
   <updated>2014-08-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/2014/08/08/Paper-planes</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;This post is not a metaphor for what started as a paper plane, and finally became the roaring jet that rules the skies.
I wish it was, but it really isn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The long awaited package from the Kickstarter funded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/393053146/powerup-30-smartphone-controlled-paper-airplane&quot;&gt;PowerUp 3.0 - Smartphone Controlled Paper Airplane project&lt;/a&gt; is finally here. I had ordered two of the basic packages for $40 each, pretty reasonable I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The package comes with the attachment for the paper planes, which is a bluetooth module connected to a propeller and a rudder.
A 1200mAh portable battery/charger comes with it, that seems to hold enough charge for hours of fun at the park.
There’s 2 printed and somewhat stiffer sheets of paper for 2 different plane models; the Invader and Nakamura.
I haven’t tried the waterproof sheets which come with template for the Nakamura model, so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First impressions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: left margin: auto&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;510&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/laser_cutting.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Laser on leather - Part 2</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/2014/07/12/Laser-on-leather-2"/>
   <updated>2014-07-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/2014/07/12/Laser-on-leather-2</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Over the one week spent ordering and waiting for the leather to get shipped to my place,
I went ahead with creating designs and trying out the Laser cutter at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://arts.uchicago.edu/hack-arts-lab-hal&quot;&gt;HAL&lt;/a&gt;.
If you are a UChicago employee or student you can walk in and reserve time with the machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the design I started with examining my own wallet to identify the absolute minimum I would carry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what it boiled down to :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A few currency bills&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 cards (3 Creditcards, 1 Transit, 1 ID, 1 Access card)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;House key&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 6 cards, of which 2 are frequently accessed, I think separate slots makes sense. With a separate compartment for currency,
a Bifold design would be the closest fit. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://noahlambert.com/shop/uni-fold-wallet&quot;&gt;uni-fold wallet&lt;/a&gt; designs by Noah Lambert was a perfect match.
I decided that a separate pouch for the key would make the wallet asymmetric and add excess thickness to the wallet, and that was dropped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dimensions are dictated by the contents the wallet would carry. The width of the wallet is the width of the dollar bill plus allowances.
The breadth should be twice the width of a standard CC (85.60mm) with allowance for the gap in the middle.
Initially I put in 2mm wide slanted slits with a separation of 2mm to guide the stitching, which ended being too close.
In the second iteration, I increased the separation to 4mm which I think is just perfect. You can get the illustrator file I used from &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/wallet-template-2.ai&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s some snaps along the way:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the laser cutter/engraver. The bright light is from the laser burning through the leather; smells nasty!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: left margin: auto&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;510&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/laser_cutting.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The edges end up charred from the Laser cutter. After cleaning, unstitched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: left margin: auto&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/unstitched.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A shot of the angular slits I got laser cut for saddle stitching. These holes were off-measurement, and I had to skip the odd ones for the stitch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: left margin: auto&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;510&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/awl_holes.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Hammering the awl head to pierce through 6mm of leather. Stitching in progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: left margin: auto&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;510&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/stitching.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Stitching done! Alternate holes are left unused, but the stitching came out beautifully!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: left margin: auto&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;510&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/saddle_stitched.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Final product. A beautiful, minimalist wallet in dark brown chromexcel leather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: left margin: auto&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;510&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/wallet_done.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
One more beauty shot :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: left margin: auto&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;510&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/wallet_done2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Laser on leather - Part 1</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/2014/07/05/Laser-on-leather-1"/>
   <updated>2014-07-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/2014/07/05/Laser-on-leather-1</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I recently got interested in Leather craft, and managed to make a couple of small leather goods at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://arts.uchicago.edu/hack-arts-lab-hal&quot;&gt;Hack Arts Lab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wallet that I’d bought from India was not only falling apart, it was also made of poor quality chome tanned leather.
Now with my newfound knowledge, I couldn’t allow myself to continue carrying such a shoddy piece of work
I wondered if I could make myself a minimalist wallet with a focus on durability with a reasonable amount of effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I find something interesting, I obsess about it. I spent an inordinate amount of time watching saddle stitching videos on youtube.
I learnt about different types of leather, tanning processes, thicknesses, crafting methods and found all of it fascinating.
I found Horween, one of the oldest tanneries in the US and it’s awesome (but proprietary) &lt;a href=&quot;http://horween.com/101/chromexcel-2/&quot;&gt;Chromexcel tanned leather&lt;/a&gt;.
Chromexcel has the reputation for being incredibly long lasting as well as developing a beautiful patina with use. I had to have this material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Horween deals with large volumes it is nearly impossible to buy small quantities from them directly. I ended up following advice from this excellent post
on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.makesupply.com/info/a-brief-guide-to-buying-horween-leather/&quot;&gt;how to buy Horween leather&lt;/a&gt; and got myself about 8 square feet of 5oz, brown Chromexcel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came across the minimalist designs by &lt;a href=&quot;http://noahlambert.com/&quot;&gt;Noah Lambert&lt;/a&gt;, and I loved the design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The making continued in Part 2.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>First month trading bitcoin</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/2013/11/08/first-month-trading-bitcoin"/>
   <updated>2013-11-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/2013/11/08/first-month-trading-bitcoin</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am not going to write about the risks and potential of Bitcoin, topics which have been
debated over in great length. Instead I would write about my first month as a newly minted
investor. This is the first time I’ve invested money in a tradeable good, and I would like
to note my mistakes and my learnings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I made the newbie mistake of watching the charts after my Bitcoins arrived in the wallet
for price drops and panic sold. “Sell high, buy low” is not as easy to follow through with
money and emotions involved. What worries me the most is that the price of bitcoin at this point
is very speculative. I do not know if it is even possible to estimate the intrinsic value of bitcoin,
and trade purely on fundamentals, especially at the timescale of weeks/months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the wildly speculative and volatile nature of bitcoin, I think that automated strategies
and bots would fare better than a trader. The bitcoin market is active 24/7 and just keeping up
with the market would place considerable strain on a trader looking to maximise time in the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I’ve ended up doing is write tests for different quantitative strategies. Here’s my repo
on some simple scripts which backtest a few simple EMA cross strategies : &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/yadudoc/Number6&quot;&gt;Number6 repo&lt;/a&gt;
The backtests are very simple and make several assumptions such as buy/sell at open/close values
of hourly candles, no crosschecks across exchanges and arbitrary buy/sell threshold. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a simulation result showing over 1M USD generated from 5K USD in the span of a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Results from running a simulation with $5000 USD with :
Starting date :  2012-12-31 16:00:00
Ending date   :  2013-12-16 05:00:00

Simulation on 1 hour candles from MtGox.
 
And basic buy threshold set to 1% of price, and sell threshold set to 3%

Format : EMA1, EMA2, EMA3, Final sum in USD
 
10, 27, 29, 1095964.1741853813
4,  6,  10, 1038221.2753517051
9,  27, 29, 1007524.4618898276
9,  28, 29, 978802.05582687503
1,  2,  3,  963086.42278712604
9,  26, 29, 959511.73509285843
10, 25, 32, 950532.6488902343
10, 26, 32, 949953.92246836261
9,  25, 29, 948698.65668256988
10, 24, 32, 943597.0524466671
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Identity</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/2013/01/17/What_am_I"/>
   <updated>2013-01-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/2013/01/17/What_am_I?</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Identity. Am I this body, flesh and mind ? Am I the mass of all thoughts and words heard and spoken ?
What is the &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; that evades my deepest introspection ? Worse still, why does it evade my understanding ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of my life, I’ve been driven by a deep instinct to be better.
Every day is a gift, to be at it, to be better than what I was yesterday.
Its no longer the destination but the whole path and process of change that entertains me.
In a way it gives reason for existence, because tomorrow will be something better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere along this path, you feel that you are caught in the stream, changing, evolving and adapting to the future.
Yet, in the few moments of clarity when you pause to make sense, you realize that you are morphing to someone who you are not.
YOU are changing. But, then you realize that you never knew who you were.
Your eyes set at a distant future, never tried to set its sight upon itself. Then you panic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have not recovered, not once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we start all over again.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>