<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Meditations</title>
 <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io"/>
 <updated>2014-12-18T19:19:50-06:00</updated>
 <id>http://yadudoc.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Yadu Nand B</name>
   <email>yadudoc1729@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Legacy</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/2014/12/18/legacy"/>
   <updated>2014-12-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/2014/12/18/legacy</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s the music that triggered this dump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;v=5p40pPd-UPc &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://img.youtube.com/vi/5p40pPd-UPc/0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Song of the Sibyl&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; border=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have spent hours in anguish pondering the seemingly unavoidable end that awaits us all.
While I have faith that technology and medicine will advance far enough to cure mitotic catastrophe,
there is no such hope in the near future, and it would be prudent to assume that no such advance is likely within my lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Becalmed</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/2014/09/02/becalmed"/>
   <updated>2014-09-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/2014/09/02/becalmed</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;You are at the sea, surrounded by the warmth of unhindered sunshine of a summer day.
There is the gentle roll of the waves, the occassional squaking of a hungry seagull.
There is calm, the comfort of the routine, and the certainity that you are not going anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It isn&amp;#8217;t the ship that is locked in the waves. The ship needs wind in its sails.
The ship mustn&amp;#8217;t fear the uncharted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am stuck as a ship, with no wind in its sails, with no &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Repertoire of classy insults</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/2014/08/23/repertoire-of-classy-insults"/>
   <updated>2014-08-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/2014/08/23/repertoire-of-classy-insults</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Scraped for Reddit, memory, and &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;I can explain it to you, but I can&amp;#8217;t comprehend it for you&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;I love how you state the obvious, with such a sense of discovery&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;d like to agree with you, but then we would both be wrong&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Do not speak unless you intend to improve the silence, please&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;You make me feel like a better person&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;When a savage speaks, silence will suffice&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;I refuse to have a batle of wits against an unarmed opponent&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Paper planes</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/2014/08/08/Paper-planes"/>
   <updated>2014-08-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/2014/08/08/Paper-planes</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;This post is not a metaphor for what started as a paper plane, and finally became the roaring jet that rules the skies.
I wish it was, but it really isn&amp;#8217;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The long awaited package from the Kickstarter funded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/393053146/powerup-30-smartphone-controlled-paper-airplane&quot;&gt;PowerUp 3.0 - Smartphone Controlled Paper Airplane project&lt;/a&gt; is finally here. I had ordered two of the basic packages for $40 each, pretty reasonable I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The package comes with the attachment for the paper planes, which is a bluetooth module connected to a propeller and a rudder.
A 1200mAh portable battery/charger comes with it, that seems to hold enough charge for hours of fun at the park.
There&amp;#8217;s 2 printed and somewhat stiffer sheets of paper for 2 different plane models; the Invader and Nakamura.
I haven&amp;#8217;t tried the waterproof sheets which come with template for the Nakamura model, so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First impressions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: left margin: auto&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;510&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;/assets/laser_cutting.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Laser on leather - Part 2</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/2014/07/12/Laser-on-leather-2"/>
   <updated>2014-07-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/2014/07/12/Laser-on-leather-2</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Over the one week spent ordering and waiting for the leather to get shipped to my place,
I went ahead with creating designs and trying out the Laser cutter at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://arts.uchicago.edu/hack-arts-lab-hal&quot;&gt;HAL&lt;/a&gt;.
If you are a UChicago employee or student you can walk in and reserve time with the machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the design I started with examining my own wallet to identify the absolute minimum I would carry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s what it boiled down to :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A few currency bills&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 cards (3 Creditcards, 1 Transit, 1 ID, 1 Access card)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;House key&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 6 cards, of which 2 are frequently accessed, I think separate slots makes sense. With a separate compartment for currency,
a Bifold design would be the closest fit. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://noahlambert.com/shop/uni-fold-wallet&quot;&gt;uni-fold wallet&lt;/a&gt; designs by Noah Lambert was a perfect match.
I decided that a separate pouch for the key would make the wallet asymmetric and add excess thickness to the wallet, and that was dropped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dimensions are dictated by the contents the wallet would carry. The width of the wallet is the width of the dollar bill plus allowances.
The breadth should be twice the width of a standard CC (85.60mm) with allowance for the gap in the middle.
Initially I put in 2mm wide slanted slits with a separation of 2mm to guide the stitching, which ended being too close.
In the second iteration, I increased the separation to 4mm which I think is just perfect. You can get the illustrator file I used from &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/wallet-template-2.ai&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s some snaps along the way:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the laser cutter/engraver. The bright light is from the laser burning through the leather; smells nasty!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: left margin: auto&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;510&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;/assets/laser_cutting.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The edges end up charred from the Laser cutter. After cleaning, unstitched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: left margin: auto&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;/assets/unstitched.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A shot of the angular slits I got laser cut for saddle stitching. These holes were off-measurement, and I had to skip the odd ones for the stitch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: left margin: auto&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;510&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;/assets/awl_holes.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Hammering the awl head to pierce through 6mm of leather. Stitching in progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: left margin: auto&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;510&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;/assets/stitching.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Stitching done! Alternate holes are left unused, but the stitching came out beautifully!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: left margin: auto&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;510&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;/assets/saddle_stitched.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Final product. A beautiful, minimalist wallet in dark brown chromexcel leather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: left margin: auto&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;510&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;/assets/wallet_done.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
One more beauty shot :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: left margin: auto&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;510&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;/assets/wallet_done2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Laser on leather - Part 1</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/2014/07/05/Laser-on-leather-1"/>
   <updated>2014-07-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/2014/07/05/Laser-on-leather-1</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I recently got interested in Leather craft, and managed to make a couple of small leather goods at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://arts.uchicago.edu/hack-arts-lab-hal&quot;&gt;Hack Arts Lab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wallet that I&amp;#8217;d bought from India was not only falling apart, it was also made of poor quality chome tanned leather.
Now with my newfound knowledge, I couldn&amp;#8217;t allow myself to continue carrying such a shoddy piece of work
I wondered if I could make myself a minimalist wallet with a focus on durability with a reasonable amount of effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I find something interesting, I obsess about it. I spent an inordinate amount of time watching saddle stitching videos on youtube.
I learnt about different types of leather, tanning processes, thicknesses, crafting methods and found all of it fascinating.
I found Horween, one of the oldest tanneries in the US and it&amp;#8217;s awesome (but proprietary) &lt;a href=&quot;http://horween.com/101/chromexcel-2/&quot;&gt;Chromexcel tanned leather&lt;/a&gt;.
Chromexcel has the reputation for being incredibly long lasting as well as developing a beautiful patina with use. I had to have this material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Horween deals with large volumes it is nearly impossible to buy small quantities from them directly. I ended up following advice from this excellent post
on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.makesupply.com/info/a-brief-guide-to-buying-horween-leather/&quot;&gt;how to buy Horween leather&lt;/a&gt; and got myself about 8 square feet of 5oz, brown Chromexcel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came across the minimalist designs by &lt;a href=&quot;http://noahlambert.com/&quot;&gt;Noah Lambert&lt;/a&gt;, and I loved the design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The making continued in Part 2.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>First month trading bitcoin</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/2013/11/08/first-month-trading-bitcoin"/>
   <updated>2013-11-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/2013/11/08/first-month-trading-bitcoin</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am not going to write about the risks and potential of Bitcoin, topics which have been
debated over in great length. Instead I would write about my first month as a newly minted
investor. This is the first time I&amp;#8217;ve invested money in a tradeable good, and I would like
to note my mistakes and my learnings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I made the newbie mistake of watching the charts after my Bitcoins arrived in the wallet
for price drops and panic sold. &amp;#8220;Sell high, buy low&amp;#8221; is not as easy to follow through with
money and emotions involved. What worries me the most is that the price of bitcoin at this point
is very speculative. I do not know if it is even possible to estimate the intrinsic value of bitcoin,
and trade purely on fundamentals, especially at the timescale of weeks/months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the wildly speculative and volatile nature of bitcoin, I think that automated strategies
and bots would fare better than a trader. The bitcoin market is active 24/7 and just keeping up
with the market would place considerable strain on a trader looking to maximise time in the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;#8217;ve ended up doing is write tests for different quantitative strategies. Here&amp;#8217;s my repo
on some simple scripts which backtest a few simple EMA cross strategies : &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/yadudoc/Number6&quot;&gt;Number6 repo&lt;/a&gt;
The backtests are very simple and make several assumptions such as buy/sell at open/close values
of hourly candles, no crosschecks across exchanges and arbitrary buy/sell threshold. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a simulation result showing over 1M USD generated from 5K USD in the span of a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Results from running a simulation with $5000 USD with :
Starting date :  2012-12-31 16:00:00
Ending date   :  2013-12-16 05:00:00

Simulation on 1 hour candles from MtGox.
 
And basic buy threshold set to 1% of price, and sell threshold set to 3%

Format : EMA1, EMA2, EMA3, Final sum in USD
 
10, 27, 29, 1095964.1741853813
4,  6,  10, 1038221.2753517051
9,  27, 29, 1007524.4618898276
9,  28, 29, 978802.05582687503
1,  2,  3,  963086.42278712604
9,  26, 29, 959511.73509285843
10, 25, 32, 950532.6488902343
10, 26, 32, 949953.92246836261
9,  25, 29, 948698.65668256988
10, 24, 32, 943597.0524466671
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Identity</title>
   <link href="http://yadudoc.github.io/2013/01/17/What_am_I%3F"/>
   <updated>2013-01-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://yadudoc.github.io/2013/01/17/What_am_I?</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Identity. Am I this body, flesh and mind ? Am I the mass of all thoughts and words heard and spoken ?
What is the &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; that evades my deepest introspection ? Worse still, why does it evade my understanding ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of my life, I&amp;#8217;ve been driven by a deep instinct to be better.
Every day is a gift, to be at it, to be better than what I was yesterday.
Its no longer the destination but the whole path and process of change that entertains me.
In a way it gives reason for existence, because tomorrow will be something better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere along this path, you feel that you are caught in the stream, changing, evolving and adapting to the future.
Yet, in the few moments of clarity when you pause to make sense, you realize that you are morphing to someone who you are not.
YOU are changing. But, then you realize that you never knew who you were.
Your eyes set at a distant future, never tried to set its sight upon itself. Then you panic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have not recovered, not once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we start all over again.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>